Vishon Singh Manhattan, New York VishonRSingh@gmail.com

https://github.com/Symbolistic https://vishonsingh.com/

I am a passionate web developer with proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB. I've been studying development since the age of 14 and worked IT for the past 5 years and now I'm ready to pursue my true passion in web development.

<u>Projects</u>

Lucid Budget

Technologies: React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Mongoose and ChartJS

Full Stack budget app using React Hooks, JWT for user authentication, Node for backend, along with MongoDB for the database. This app fully utilizes the MERN stack.

Movie App

Technologies: React, Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB and Mongoose

This clone utilizes TMDb API with JWT user authentication. This uses the MERN stack and is hosted on Heroku, this utilizes Redux to help handle the user data from the JWT token.

Weather App

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

Grabs current location and displays weather in Celsius or Fahrenheit using OpenWeatherMap API and React Hooks. It also has a search option to search other locations for current weather.

Experience

Consultation and Repair Agent at Geek Squad

2016 - Current

- Diagnosed Hardware and Software issues for client computers, phones, tablets, and other devices.
- Replaced iPhone screens and batteries, helped verify liquid damage, and troubleshoot software issue

Freelance Web Developer

2016 - 2017

- Created and sold SPA's to internet & affiliate marketers which increased ROI of product sales
- Created specialized website designs based on the clients target audience and the items they promoted

Freelance Computer Technician

2008 - 2016

- Provided Computer Repair Services and Technical Support to private local residences and schools.
- Assisted teachers and school personnel with technical setups and programming for individual classes

Education

FreeCodeCamp Completed: 2020

Full Stack Web Developer Certification

Queensborough Community College

Health Sciences

Completed: 2015